<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Raleigh Real Estate Podcast with Greg Ismay</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Ismay Realty Group - your professional Raleigh Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Greg Ismay</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-06-12 13:19:36 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Greg Ismay</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Greg@IsmayRealtyGroup.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Greg Ismay</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Raleigh Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Ismay Realty Group - your professional Raleigh Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Youre Not Getting Any Younger - Multigen Living Can Save Your Money and Health</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/selling-home-get-free-home-value-report.html</link>
        
          <category>Raleigh Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-29 13:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2018/Multi-Generational+Living+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Over the past several years, I’ve been seeing a trend where buyers look for homes that will accommodate multiple generations—grandparents, parents, kids, and grandkids.


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


My gut tells me that there is a demographic shift occurring here, where:
  1. Grandparents or empty-nesters are becoming more inclined to live with people of other generations, and/or:
  2. Younger generations are more inclined to have their parents or grandparents living with them.

Since we’re all living longer, the older generations might feel the pressure of housing costs. Secondly, as people try to downsize in today’s marketplace, it’s important to know that buying a smaller home doesn’t always mean that the costs are lower. Typically people are looking for different floor plans, possibly those with main-level living, and those properties can be more costly.

Conversely for the younger generation, having the parents or grandparents around could be helpful in regards to caring for children. I also think that this younger generation might worry for their parents as they slow down with age; as they lose mobility and develop medical issues, they need more attention, and their younger counterparts want to be there to ensure they’re safe and comfortable.

“SINCE WE’RE ALL LIVING LONGER, THE OLDER GENERATIONS MIGHT FEEL THE PRESSURE ON HOUSING COSTS.”

Putting these factors together, many people have asked about what opportunities there are where they can bring the whole family together. Some big builders are starting to build what they call multigenerational plans in which they’ve accommodated into the floor plan a space where the parents and grandparents can have their own space, alongside the general or main living areas with the rest of the family.

In order to accommodate multiple generations, they might move, eliminate, or add some walls. They might make the basement a fully furnished space (with a kitchen and bathroom) with a separate entrance from the main door to foster privacy for the occupants. Additionally, if the property is large enough, then a guest house could be considered.

If you have any questions about accommodating multigenerational living, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help and advise you however I can.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2018/Multi-Generational+Living+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2018/Multi-Generational+Living+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Over the past several years, I’ve been seeing a trend where buyers look for homes that will accommodate multiple generations—grandparents, parents, kids, and grandkids.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Over the past several years, I’ve been seeing a trend where buyers look for homes that will accommodate multiple generations—grandparents, parents, kids, and grandkids.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Keep Radon Out of Your Home and Keep Your Family Safe</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/keep-radon-out-of-your-home-and-keep.html</link>
        
          <category>Raleigh Community Spotlight</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-17 09:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2018/Let%2527s+Talk+About+Radon+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m joined by Randy Paquette of First Choice Radon to discuss what you can do to prevent radon from seeping into your home.


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


As a gas, radon is the leading cause of lung cancer in the U.S. among non-smokers. It also kills more people annually than breast cancer, colon cancer, and prostate cancer combined.

The good news is, radon is easy to test for, and you can do it with several different monitors. Randy suggests that you test for radon annually, even if you have a radon system already installed in your house. If you don’t have access to professional radon testing, you can use a home kit. Home kits take about 48 hours. After the test is done, you send the kit to a lab, which then sends you back your results.

If your numbers come back a little high, you should have a professional then test your home so you know exactly what the levels are. Once you know what the levels are, the next step is to mitigate them. If you have a basement or a slab home, they create a vacuum under your home using a sub-slab system (or “fan system” as some call it), which sucks the radon out before it can get inside.

“IN THE LONG RUN, THE COST OF PROTECTING YOUR FAMILY FROM RADON IS WORTH THE INVESTMENT.”

If you have a crawl space home, this process takes a little more work, so the cost is a little different. Basement and slab-home mitigations cost about $1,300, but the system itself should last anywhere between 10 to 30 years, so the annual cost is negligible. It only costs about $2 per month to operate the system, which is also a negligible amount.

A single test costs roughly $150. North Carolina is what’s referred to as a “red state,” meaning homes here typically have higher levels of radon in them, so $150 is a sensible investment to protect your family from something as potentially dangerous as radon is.

If you have any more questions about radon or radon testing or you have any other real estate needs I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2018/Let%2527s+Talk+About+Radon+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2018/Let%2527s+Talk+About+Radon+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m joined by Randy Paquette of First Choice Radon to discuss what you can do to prevent radon from seeping into your home.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m joined by Randy Paquette of First Choice Radon to discuss what you can do to prevent radon from seeping into your home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Buyers and Sellers Must Know About Our Spring Market</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-buyers-and-sellers-must-know-about.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-04 13:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2018/Your+Spring+Market+Update+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The month of March has been cold and dreary here in the Raleigh area. So, when I say that it’s time to get ready for the spring market, many people think, “Spring market? It’s still winter!”


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


However, despite the cold, spring has definitely arrived. The spring real estate market has sprung. I recently looked at all homes listed on our MLS in the last 30 days, and I found that 62% of those properties are already under contract.

This tells us that the market is at a blistering pace. So, today I’d like to bring you some tips on how to prepare if you plan to buy or sell in our spring or summer market.

Let’s start by talking about buyers. If you’re thinking of making a home purchase this year, I recommend that you do so sooner rather than later. Interest rates are sliding up a little bit and many predict this trend will continue into the future. So, make your move as soon as you can.

The first step to take as a buyer is to get with a good lender and get pre-approved. This will give you a good starting place for your home search. Once you’ve met with a trusted local lender, you’ll need to find a good agent. The right agent will not only be able to help you strategize your home search, but they will also be able to help you find properties that haven’t come to the market yet. Additionally, a good agent will help you make faster decisions, which will be beneficial in our fast-paced market.

“LISTINGS ARE MOVING QUICKLY, BUT MORE INVENTORY WILL BE COMING TO OUR MARKET SOON.”

As for sellers, you may want to wait until the summer to make your move. This is especially the case if you have children since they will be out of school during this time and more family-style homes tend to be listed at this time of year. That said, now is the best time to focus on getting your home ready for the market. That way when it comes time to list, you will be well-prepared. Listings are moving quickly, but more inventory will be coming to our market soon.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2018/Your+Spring+Market+Update+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2018/Your+Spring+Market+Update+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The month of March has been cold and dreary here in the Raleigh area. So, when I say that it’s time to get ready for the spring market, many people think, “Spring market? It’s still winter!”

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The month of March has been cold and dreary here in the Raleigh area. So, when I say that it’s time to get ready for the spring market, many people think, “Spring market? It’s still winter!”

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>You Never Know What Issues a Home Might Have</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/you-never-know-what-issues-home-might.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-08 12:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2018/Answering+Common+Questions+On+Home+Inspections+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Let’s talk about home inspections.


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


Beyond a general home inspection, there are several specific inspections buyers may choose to conduct while under contract.

Radon inspections, termite inspections, and others are all options, depending on the features of the property and the buyer’s concerns.

If, during a general inspection, the home inspector finds fault with any of the features they examine, additional inspections may be ordered to further evaluate the specific issue. When specific issues are uncovered, it can be beneficial to have a specialized expert take a closer look.

Even in the case of new construction homes, the issues an inspection can uncover will more than justify the cost of the process. A home inspection usually costs around $500, with additional inspections costing between $100 and $150.

Some buyers wonder why they can’t just inspect the home on their own. Technically this is an option, but if the buyer plans to use the inspection report to pursue negotiations with the seller, a licensed inspector is best.

“WHEN SPECIFIC ISSUES ARE UNCOVERED, IT CAN BE BENEFICIAL TO HAVE A SPECIALIZED EXPERT TAKE A CLOSER LOOK.”

It isn’t only buyers who can order a home inspection. Many sellers have asked me recently if they should order one before listing their property. This isn’t always advisable, but if a home is more than 10 years old, there are absolutely some advantages to doing so.

When a seller orders an inspection before listing, they can get issues addressed ahead of time. It also gives them more leverage in terms of marketing the home.

These are just a few key points on what you need to know about home inspections. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2018/Answering+Common+Questions+On+Home+Inspections+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2018/Answering+Common+Questions+On+Home+Inspections+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Let’s talk about home inspections.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Let’s talk about home inspections.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Ways to Make Your 2018 Move as Smooth as Possible </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-ways-to-make-your-2018-move-as-smooth.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-31 10:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you are thinking about buying a house in the 2018 spring market, there are a number of things you can do to put yourself in a strong position when getting ready to make your move.


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


Here are a few pointers on how to get ahead of things if you plan on making a move in the coming year:

1. Check your credit score. Most people think that they’re in good shape, but the fact is that there are some derogatories that can find their way onto your report. Those problems can take time to clean up, so make sure that you look at that ahead of time.

2. Start looking at homes and neighborhoods. Consider things that the home will deliver for you. If you have a growing family, you may need more space. If you are downsizing, you may need a master bedroom on the main level. Start looking around and make a preliminary checklist.

3. Keep tabs on interest rates. Shop for a lender, too. You need to get pre-approved, and it’s better to do that sooner rather than later.

4. If you own your home, you need to put a plan together to get maximum value from your home sale. This includes things like staging, repairs, or making some upgrades to make your home more attractive to potential buyers. Get an idea of what you can net from the sale and put that into the financing for your next home.

“GET APPROVED SOONER RATHER THAN LATER.”

Do you want to get the equity out of your current home first and move into temporary housing while you shop for your next home? Or do you want to go for a same-day closing on both properties? Each of these strategies has its own set of advantages and disadvantages, so let me know if you have any questions.

5. Interview potential real estate brokers. Find one who can provide the best service and help you find a home or get the maximum value for your current home.

As always, if you have any questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you are thinking about buying a house in the 2018 spring market, there are a number of things you can do to put yourself in a strong position when getting ready to make your move.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you are thinking about buying a house in the 2018 spring market, there are a number of things you can do to put yourself in a strong position when getting ready to make your move.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have You Set Any Goals for the New Year?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/have-you-set-any-goals-for-new-year.html</link>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-02 12:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Goals—now that we’re in the new year, what are your goals? Do you have them written down? Are you reviewing them on a regular basis? If not, here are some things that you may want to consider that may help you set, stick to, and achieve your goals.


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


Most anything you read about goal-setting states that if you write your goals down, you’re 80% more likely to achieve them. For years, I had goals that I kept in my head but never wrote down. I don’t think I was nearly as effective in achieving them.

Some authors on goal-setting even suggest that it’s a good idea to review your goals daily, first thing in the morning when you wake up and as the last thing you do before you go to bed at night. That may seem excessive for some, but the whole point to that conversation is to make sure that once you get your goals written down, you don’t let 12 months pass before you review them again. You should choose whatever is going to be a good process for you to be checking on your own goals.

I’d like to share a tool I use which I’ve found helpful in terms of setting a goal, as well as placing underpinnings beneath that goal that will help you review your progress and overall process.

“IF YOU WRITE YOUR GOALS DOWN, YOU’RE 80% MORE LIKELY TO ACHIEVE THEM.”

Suppose my goal is to lose 10 pounds. This time of year, it’s always especially difficult with the number of holiday dinners that we’re exposed to. To help with that goal, I’ve drafted a “1-3-5” form. To make one for yourself, you should:

• Write one goal at the top of the form.
  • Devise three strategies that will help you achieve those goals. Write them laterally beneath your goal.
  • For each strategy, come up with five different tactics that you can measure and develop to meet your goal. Write those in the columns beneath each strategy.

For losing 10 pounds, my three strategies are to generally improve my diet, lift weights and work out three days a week, and to do cardio exercises two days of the week. To illustrate the purpose of the 1-3-5 form, I’ve created five tactics for eating better:


  Taking a protein shake once a day.
  Cutting soda from my diet.
  Cutting fast food from my diet.
  No dessert.
  Stop eating past 6 p.m.


With this, I’m able to develop not only a goal, but put some underpinnings on it as well. I can check this form on a daily basis to hold myself accountable for achieving my goal.

If you have any questions about goal-setting, please reach out to me. I’d love to hear some of your goals and strategies for achieving them.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Goals—now that we’re in the new year, what are your goals? Do you have them written down? Are you reviewing them on a regular basis? If not, here are some things that you may want to consider that may help you set, stick to, and achieve your goals.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Goals—now that we’re in the new year, what are your goals? Do you have them written down? Are you reviewing them on a regular basis? If not, here are some things that you may want to consider that may help you set, stick to, and achieve your goals.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What the Ismay Realty Group Is Thankful for This Year</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-ismay-realty-group-is-thankful-for.html</link>
        
          <category>Client Appreciation</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-18 15:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

As we approach the end of the year and prepare for 2018, it’s a good time to reflect on the blessings we’ve seen in 2017. I recently learned that when you write down the things you’re grateful for, a chemical reaction occurs in your brain which leads to feelings of joy.


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


This is a proven fact, so why not give it a try? If you’d like to let me know what you are grateful for this year, get in touch. I’d love to hear from you.

Here at the Ismay Realty Group, we’re grateful for a few things. First of all, we’re grateful for our office manager, Robyn. Robyn has been with us a long time, and despite some medical hardships this year, she has been recovering well. She’s still receiving some treatments, but is getting stronger all the time.

“WE’RE SO GRATEFUL FOR ALL OF YOU.”

The second thing we’re grateful for is all of you: our clients. We appreciate everyone who has trusted their transaction to us over this past year.

We’re also thankful for all of the great vendors we work with. We know people who specialize in flooring, paint, tax preparation, and more. So, if you ever need a recommendation, we’ve got you covered.

Another thing we’re grateful for is our area. Between our great real estate and job markets, our amazing quality of life, and our fantastic economy, our team is very happy to live here.

I hope your holiday season is happy and safe. I’ll see you next year.

If you have any real estate questions, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As we approach the end of the year and prepare for 2018, it’s a good time to reflect on the blessings we’ve seen in 2017. I recently learned that when you write down the things you’re grateful for, a chemical reaction occurs in your brain which leads to feelings of joy.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As we approach the end of the year and prepare for 2018, it’s a good time to reflect on the blessings we’ve seen in 2017. I recently learned that when you write down the things you’re grateful for, a chemical reaction occurs in your brain which leads to feelings of joy.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don't Let This Ruin Your Home Sale</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/check-your-crawl-space-before-you-put.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-30 09:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Is+Your+Crawl+Space+Up+to+Date%253F+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you are preparing your home for the market, you need to check on your crawl space.


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


You may say, “Why would I even want to think about the crawl space? I don’t want to go look at it. There are spiders down there!”

I completely understand where you are coming from. Like the saying goes: Out of sight, out of mind. However, we’ve had several clients experience delays and costly surprises during their transactions thanks to their crawl space. These issues could have been avoided with some preparation up front.

When you look at your crawl space, there are a few things to watch out for.

“AVOID COSTLY REPAIRS AND DELAYS BY CHECKING OUT THE CRAWL SPACE UP FRONT.”

1. The insulation is hanging down. If you see this, that could mean that moisture levels have risen above the acceptable level. If that’s the case, you should also look for small leaks in any pipes and get those taken care of. Check for water around the foundation as well. It could be that your gutters are clogged, that your downspouts aren’t draining properly, or that you need extensions for your downspouts.

2. Is your vapor barrier in good condition? The vapor barrier should not be torn. Make sure that it is spread out evenly and that it covers the majority of the dirt floor in the crawl space.

3. Termite bond. If you have a company that checks your property, they will do moisture readings in the crawl space. A lack of moisture helps prevent termites. If you don’t have a termite bond, it might be worth your while to get a termite inspection before you put your home on the market.

These are just a few things you can do to avoid any delays or costly repairs once you get your home on the market and under contract.

If you have any other questions about crawl space maintenance or preparing your home for the market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Is+Your+Crawl+Space+Up+to+Date%253F+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Is+Your+Crawl+Space+Up+to+Date%253F+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you are preparing your home for the market, you need to check on your crawl space.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you are preparing your home for the market, you need to check on your crawl space.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>10 Reasons to Consider Selling During the Holiday Season</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/10-reasons-to-consider-selling-during.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-08 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/10+Reasons+to+List+in+the+Fall+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Although spring is traditionally considered the best time to sell a home, today I’m excited to share the top 10 reasons you should consider listing in the next few months before the spring market hits.


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


10. You will have the opportunity to be a non-contingent buyer in the spring. In the spring, there are more homes available on the market. By listing now, you can sell high and buy low in the spring.

9. You can restrict showings during the holidays. They don’t have to upset your family time.

8. January is when employees start new jobs. Since transfer employees can’t wait until spring to buy, you’ll need to be on the market at the end of the year to capture those buyers.

7. People are looking to buy for tax reasons.

6. People have more time to look for homes. Because people often take off work during the holidays, they will be freer to spend time searching the market than other times of the year.

“LESS COMPETITION ON THE MARKET MEANS MORE EYES ON YOUR PROPERTY.”

5. Buyers are more emotional. During the holidays, people become sentimental and may be more likely to pay a higher price.

4. Houses show better when they are decorated for the holidays. Everyone loves seasonal decor, so homes at this time of year are more attractive.

3. Supply will dramatically increase as the spring market ramps up in January. This will lead to less demand, and less demand means less money in your pocket.

2. Serious buyers have fewer options. During fall and winter months, there is less competition on the market. This puts your listing at an advantage.

1. People who look for homes at this time of year are much more serious about buying.

If you have any other questions or would like more information about selling your home this time of year, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/10+Reasons+to+List+in+the+Fall+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/10+Reasons+to+List+in+the+Fall+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Although spring is traditionally considered the best time to sell a home, today I’m excited to share the top 10 reasons you should consider listing in the next few months before the spring market hits.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Although spring is traditionally considered the best time to sell a home, today I’m excited to share the top 10 reasons you should consider listing in the next few months before the spring market hits.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Out-of-Pocket Costs Homebuyers Should Expect </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/4-out-of-pocket-costs-homebuyers-should.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-09 11:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Costs+Buyers+Should+Plan+For+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When buying a home, there are four out-of-pocket expenses that you should be prepared to pay:


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


1. Your due diligence deposit. Our purchase contract was revised a few years ago and now stipulates that the buyer make a non-refundable due diligence deposit to the seller. This deposit does credit back to the transaction as long as you make it to the closing table. The due diligence deposits can range anywhere from $500 to several thousand dollars, depending on the price of the property and the competitive pressure against the property.

2. The earnest money deposit. This is another deposit from the buyer to the seller, in addition to the due diligence deposit. Like the due diligence deposit, the earnest money deposit credits back to the transaction at closing. The earnest money deposit can range from $1,000 to several thousand dollars, again depending on the price of the property and the amount of pressure on the property at the time of contract.

3. Home inspections. A general inspection, termite inspection, and radon inspection are the big three that you’ll want to order. Home inspections range from $700 to $800 overall. That said, there may be additional inspections required based on what the initial inspections find. If the property has a well or septic tank, those require their own inspections. Generally, though, expect to pay $700 to $800. Those expenses can be moved to the settlement statement, but it’s good to know that amount up front for planning purposes.

4. Other fees and service costs. Depending on your lender, you will have to pay some costs for the appraisal process, application fee, and more. These other services usually cost a few hundred dollars.

“THE EARNEST MONEY DEPOSIT CREDITS BACK TO THE TRANSACTION AT CLOSING.”

These are the four main costs that you should plan for when buying a home.

If you have any other questions about the home buying process or our current real estate market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Costs+Buyers+Should+Plan+For+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Costs+Buyers+Should+Plan+For+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When buying a home, there are four out-of-pocket expenses that you should be prepared to pay:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When buying a home, there are four out-of-pocket expenses that you should be prepared to pay:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Accessing Our Newsletter Just Got Easier</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/accessing-our-newsletter-just-got-easier.html</link>
        
          <category>Client Appreciation</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-21 11:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Check+Out+Our+Newsletter+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I was just talking recently with a past client, Lori, who had a great idea. As you may know, we do have a newsletter available.


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


“NOW WE HAVE ARCHIVES OF OUR PAST AND CURRENT NEWSLETTERS ON THE BLOG.”

This newsletter contains information on the market, vendors, local happenings, and success stories as well.

This brings me to Lori’s great idea. It all started when she realized she’d gone to work without bringing along our newsletter.

For this reason, she suggested that we find a way to put copies of our newsletter up on our blog.

So, my team and I made it happen. Now we have archives of our past and current newsletters on the blog.

For those of you who don’t receive our newsletter, please let me know and I’ll get you on the list.

If you have any great ideas like this one or a question you’d like to see in our video, we’d love to hear it.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Check+Out+Our+Newsletter+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Check+Out+Our+Newsletter+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I was just talking recently with a past client, Lori, who had a great idea. As you may know, we do have a newsletter available.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I was just talking recently with a past client, Lori, who had a great idea. As you may know, we do have a newsletter available.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can an Agent Help You With a New Construction Purchase?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-can-agent-help-you-with-new.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-31 08:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/How+Can+an+Agent+Help+You+With+a+New+Construction+Purpose%253F+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Why is being a represented buyer so important to the purchase of a new construction home? There are more reasons than you may think.


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


If you have been considering purchasing a new home, it’s absolutely vital that you hire an agent to represent you.

Even if you are not in the market for a new home at the moment, this information may still be pertinent to you in the future.

As of late, many people have begun to shift the focus of their home search from resale properties to new construction. In the majority of popular price ranges in 2017, in fact, one in every three homes sold is a new construction.

New construction purchases are becoming more and more popular as time goes on.

What does all of this mean in terms of you hiring your own agent?

First of all, the builder rep, or on-site agent, has a fiduciary responsibility to the seller. An on-site agent is there with the express purpose of getting the best deal for the seller—they are simply not looking out for your best interests.

“HAVING AN EXTRA SET OF EYES AND EARS ON THE BUILDING PROCESS WILL BE EXTREMELY HELPFUL.”

Only your own agent will truly work toward getting you the best deal. Nevertheless, one of the primary reasons people tend to believe they should forego representation is cost.

The cost of hiring an agent, however, is massively inconsequential compared to the money, opportunity, and peace of mind you gain from professional representation in a real estate transaction. As a matter of fact, the on-site agent, as well, would prefer you have representation.

Working directly with another agent will not only help you but also everyone involved, to achieve as smooth a deal as possible.

Another factor to consider in terms of cost is that add-ons, like fencing, could push the price of the property above what it was listed at. Even though you may be paying a slightly higher price, working with an agent will still greatly aid you in obtaining the greatest value possible.

But, financial benefits are not all you gain from being represented. Having an extra set of eyes and ears on the building process will be extremely helpful in making sure that you are protected.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/How+Can+an+Agent+Help+You+With+a+New+Construction+Purpose%253F+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/How+Can+an+Agent+Help+You+With+a+New+Construction+Purpose%253F+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Why is being a represented buyer so important to the purchase of a new construction home? There are more reasons than you may think.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Why is being a represented buyer so important to the purchase of a new construction home? There are more reasons than you may think.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have You Been to Some of These Great Venues in Raleigh? </title>
        <link>localhost:4000/have-you-been-to-some-of-these-great.html</link>
        
          <category>Raleigh Community Spotlight</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-10 18:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Have+You+Been+to+Some+of+These+Great+Venues+in+Raleigh%253F+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you looking for something fun and different to do here in Raleigh? I have a list of great venues and activities for you today.


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


There are a lot of great things to do in our area, so if you get an itch to go out, here are a few different places for you to check out:

First, make sure to visit the Koka Booth Ampitheatre for weekly movies on the lawn and weekly concerts, which include country music, bluegrass, and rock and roll. They even host the North Carolina symphony on occasion.

The art museum also features weekly movies on the lawn and concerts.

Speaking of music, North Hills has its annual summer beach series going on right now; you can check that out each Thursday night. In the fall, they will switch over to their tribute band series on Friday nights.

“DON’T MISS RALEIGH RESTAURANT WEEK—EXPLORE DOWNTOWN AND ENJOY SOME GREAT FOOD!”

If you are looking for some major acts, look no further than the Walnut Creek Amphitheatre. Upcoming concerts include Foreigner, John Mayer, Luke Bryan, Green Day, and more.

If you’ve been waiting for a reason to check out downtown Raleigh, don’t miss Raleigh Restaurant Week from August 21st through the 27th. This is a great time to explore the downtown area and enjoy some great food.

We also have some great professional sports. From the Durham Bulls to the Carolina Mudcats, there is still plenty of baseball to see this year. Soon, hockey players will be ready to take the ice.

North Carolina is a college sports mecca, with Duke and North Carolina football teams getting ready to take the field. After that comes basketball. So, all throughout the year, we have some real quality sports teams to watch.

When it comes to art, culture, and museums, there are a lot of great venues to consider:

• The UNC Arboretum
  • The UNC Playmakers Repertory Theatre Company
  • The Duke Art Museum
  • The North Carolina Museum of Art
  • The North Carolina Museum of Life and Science in Durham
  • The North Carolina History Museum
  • The Carolina Ballet
  • The North Carolina State Assembly Legislature
  • The Governor’s Mansion
  • That is just a brief rundown of some very interesting venues and great places to go for inexpensive entertainment here in the area.

If you have any questions about what it’s like to live in Raleigh or would like to learn more about our local real estate market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Have+You+Been+to+Some+of+These+Great+Venues+in+Raleigh%253F+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Have+You+Been+to+Some+of+These+Great+Venues+in+Raleigh%253F+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Are you looking for something fun and different to do here in Raleigh? I have a list of great venues and activities for you today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Are you looking for something fun and different to do here in Raleigh? I have a list of great venues and activities for you today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Want to See One of Our Newest Homes for Sale?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/want-to-see-one-of-our-newest-homes-for.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-21 15:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Want+to+See+One+of+Our+Newest+Homes+for+Sale%253F+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re offering you a sneak peek of a beautiful ranch-style property coming on the market this Saturday.


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


Follow along with me in the video above for a guided tour of the exterior of a gorgeous property we’re putting on the market this Saturday.

This is a custom-built home that was built for the developer of this particular neighborhood who also developed several other high-end neighborhoods in Wake Forest. We’re pricing this home to sell, so there will be a lot of demand for it. We’ll run open houses for it on both Saturday and Sunday, and our goal is to have it sold by Monday when the homeowner gets back from their beach trip.

So what does the outside of this single-story, ranch-style home have to offer?

Starting out front, a nice, big driveway circles all the way around the yard and affords a lot of space for parking. Since this home is located on the west side of US 1 in Wake Forest, this area isn’t as congested with traffic as what you would see on the east side. The lot this property sits on is well-treed, and the canopy of shade keeps things much cooler on a hot summer day.

“COME JOIN US SATURDAY OR SUNDAY FOR A CLOSER LOOK AT THIS GREAT PROPERTY.”

As you can see, the current homeowner does his due diligence in terms of landscaping. He selected the home’s exterior color scheme so it would showcase the cedar shake roof, which was redone in 2008 and was recently inspected and serviced. If you’re not familiar with cedar shake roofing, it’s designed to last longer than asphalt shingles.

If you’re looking for single-level living, it’s tough to find a ranch-style home with all of the bedrooms on the same level. In this home, the master bedroom and the study are on one side, and the other bedrooms are on the other.

Rounding out the tour, the back of the home is bulwarked by a very generous deck that spans almost its entire length, and farther out in the backyard lies a scenic pond stocked with fish.

If you or someone you know is interested in this property, come join us this Saturday or Sunday or give us a call so we can schedule a private tour of the inside.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Want+to+See+One+of+Our+Newest+Homes+for+Sale%253F+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Want+to+See+One+of+Our+Newest+Homes+for+Sale%253F+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today we’re offering you a sneak peek of a beautiful ranch-style property coming on the market this Saturday.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today we’re offering you a sneak peek of a beautiful ranch-style property coming on the market this Saturday.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Frustrated With the Marketplace? We Have a Solution</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/frustrated-with-marketplace-we-have.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Greg Ismay</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-14 11:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Frustrated+With+the+Marketplace%253F+We+Have+a+Solution+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our strategic home buying consultation will alleviate your frustration as a buyer and help you find the home of your dreams.


Selling a home? Get a free home value report
Buying a home? Search all homes for sale


We’ve been noticing a lot of frustration from buyers in the marketplace lately about the home search process. That’s too bad, because we believe this should be a joyful and fulfilling experience. With that in mind, we’ve cracked the code to help buyers get through the ambivalence and anxiety of the home search process with a strategic home buying consultation.

Look at it this way—there aren’t many important things in life you wouldn’t develop a strategy to address to ensure your success, right? Unfortunately, when addressing the home buying process, people oftentimes go online and start looking at properties in the marketplace without thinking about the strategy they’ll use to win in the marketplace.

Buying a home is the most expensive purchase many people will make in their lifetime, so it absolutely requires strategy and focus. This is where our strategic home buying consultation comes in.

The first step to this consultation is to understand the needs, wants, and desires of all parties involved in the process. Find out what they are and hit those targets. There may be some give and take, but doing that up front will prepare you to be more successful in the marketplace.

The second step is to figure out your motivation. When there’s a home that needs to be sold in order to purchase the perfect home—whether it’s a trade-up or trade-down home—there can be a conflict of motivation. Are you more interested in finding the perfect property to motivate you to actually move? If so, the danger there is once you find that perfect property, your current home isn’t ready to be marketed. If you’re more interested in getting your current home on the market, the danger there is once it’s under contract, you’ll have nowhere to go.

“BUYING A HOME ABSOLUTELY REQUIRES STRATEGY AND FOCUS.”

Lastly, you have to know what you can afford. Many first-time homebuyers don’t know what they can afford or what mortgage loan products are available to them. Because of this, they wait until they can build up their down payment or credit score to where they think it should be without realizing they’re probably already qualified to purchase. The longer you wait, the more home prices and interest rates may rise. It might be more advantageous for you to move forward now.

The whole point of our strategic consultation is to determine whether the time is now for you to buy a home. You’d be surprised at what we can get accomplished in 60 minutes by sitting down with folks and developing a strategic plan. This will help you enjoy the process of finding your dream home.

If you have any questions about this process or you’re a homebuyer and it sounds like something that might interest you, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Frustrated+With+the+Marketplace%253F+We+Have+a+Solution+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Greg+Ismay/Videos/2017/Frustrated+With+the+Marketplace%253F+We+Have+a+Solution+-+Raleigh+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Our strategic home buying consultation will alleviate your frustration as a buyer and help you find the home of your dreams.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Greg Ismay</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Our strategic home buying consultation will alleviate your frustration as a buyer and help you find the home of your dreams.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Raleigh, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Greg Ismay</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Greg Ismay</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Ismay Realty Group - your professional Raleigh Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
